Tej Chajed

Curriculum Vitae



Research Interests

I work on formal verification for systems software. In my research I develop **realistic**, **performant systems**, specify their intended behavior, then prove that the implementation always meet the specification. My PhD research culminated in a **verified**, **concurrent file system** with a proof that your data is safe if the computer suddenly reboots, and which gets good performance.

Education

- 2014–2022 **Ph.D. in Computer Science**, MIT, Cambridge, MA Verifying a concurrent, crash-safe file system with sequential reasoning
- 2014–2017 M.S. in Computer Science, GPA: 4.0/4.0, MIT, Cambridge, MA Verifying an I/O-concurrent file system
- 2010–2014 **B.S. in Electrical Engineering and Computer Science**, GPA: 3.97/4.0, University of Illinois, Urbana, IL

Positions

- 2023–present Assistant professor, University of Wisconsin-Madison
 - 2022–2023 **Postdoctoral researcher**, at VMware Research
 - 2014–2022 **Research assistant**, at MIT in the PDOS group advised by Frans Kaashoek, Nickolai Zeldovich, and Joseph Tassarotti

Conference Publications

- HotStorage Shadow Filesystems: Recovering from Filesystem Runtime Errors via 2024 Robust Alternative Execution
 - Jing Liu, Xiangpeng Hao, Andrea Arpaci-Dusseau, Remzi Arpaci-Dusseau, Tej Chajed
- OSDI 2024 Inductive Invariants That Spark Joy: Using Invariant Taxonomies to Streamline Distributed Protocol Proofs
 - Tony Nuda Zhang, Travis Hance, Manos Kapritsos, Tej Chajed, Bryan Parno
- OSDI 2024 Anvil: Verifying Liveness of Cluster Management Controllers
 Xudong Sun, Wenjie Ma, Jiawei Tyler Gu, Zicheng Ma, *Tej Chajed*, Jon Howell, Andrea
 Lattuada, Oded Padon, Lalith Suresh, Adriana Szekeres, Tianyin Xu
- HotOS 2024 Beyond isolation: OS verification as a foundation for correct applications
 - Matthias Brun, Reto Achermann, *Tej Chajed*, Jon Howell, Gerd Zellweger, Andrea Lattuada

- VLDB 2023 DBSP: Automatic Incremental View Maintenance for Rich Query Mihai Budiu, Tej Chajed, Frank McSherry, Leonid Ryzhyk, Val Tannen OSDI 2022 Verifying the DaisyNFS concurrent and crash-safe file system with sequential reasoning Tej Chajed, Joseph Tassarotti, Mark Theng, M. Frans Kaashoek, Nickolai Zeldovich OSDI 2021 GoJournal: a verified, concurrent, crash-safe journaling system Tej Chajed, Joseph Tassarotti, Mark Theng, Ralf Jung, M. Frans Kaashoek, Nickolai Zeldovich SOSP 2019 Verifying concurrent, crash-safe systems with Perennial Tej Chajed, Joseph Tassarotti, M. Frans Kaashoek, Nickolai Zeldovich Security 2019 EverParse: Verified Secure Zero-Copy Parsers for Authenticated Message Formats Tahina Ramananandro, Antoine Delignat-Lavaud, Cédric Fournet, Nikhil Swamy, Tej Chajed, Nadim Kobeissi, Jonathan Protzenko PLDI 2019 Argosy: Verifying Layered Storage Systems with Recovery Refinement Tej Chajed, Joseph Tassarotti, M. Frans Kaashoek, Nickolai Zeldovich OSDI 2018 Verifying concurrent software using movers in CSPEC Tej Chajed, M. Frans Kaashoek, Butler Lampson, and Nickolai Zeldovich OSDI 2018 Proving confidentiality in a file system using DiskSec Atalay İleri, Tej Chajed, Adam Chlipala, M. Frans Kaashoek, Nickolai Zeldovich SOSP 2017 Verifying a high-performance crash-safe file system using a tree speci-Haogang Chen, Tej Chajed, Alex Konradi, Stephanie Wang, Atalay Ileri, Adam Chlipala, M. Frans Kaashoek, Nickolai Zeldovich SOSP 2015 Using Crash Hoare Logic for certifying the FSCQ file system Haogang Chen, Daniel Ziegler, Tej Chajed, Adam Chlipala, M. Frans Kaashoek, and Nickolai Zeldovich SoCC 2013 Natjam: design and evaluation of eviction policies for supporting priorities and deadlines in mapreduce clusters Brian Cho, Muntasir Rahman, Tej Chajed, Indranil Gupta, Cristina Abad, Nathan Roberts, Philbert Lin Workshop Papers
- CoqPL 2021 Record Updates in Coq Tej Chajed
- CoqPL 2020 Verifying concurrent Go code in Coq with Goose

 Tej Chajed, Joseph Tassarotti, M. Frans Kaashoek, Nickolai Zeldovich
- HotOS 2015 **Amber: Decoupling user data from web applications** *Tej Chajed*, Jon Gjengset, Jelle van den Hooff, M. Frans Kaashoek, James Mickens, Robert Morris, Nickolai Zeldovich

Teaching Experiences

Fall 2023 Instructor, CS 839: Systems verification, UW-Madison Fall 2020 TA, 6.826 (Principles of Computer Systems), MIT Fall 2019 TA, 6.826 (Principles of Computer Systems), MIT Fall 2017 TA, 6.826 (Principles of Computer Systems), MIT Spring 2017 Course development, 6.826 (Principles of Computer Systems), MIT During this time I designed and implemented the programming assignments for 6.826. Mentorship 2022 Mark Theng (master's thesis) 2021 Sharon Lin, undergrad 2020 Sydney Gibson (master's thesis) 2019 Eleftherios Ioannidis (master's thesis) 2017 Alex Konradi (master's thesis) 2017 Daniel Ziegler (<u>master's thesis</u>) Industry Experience Summer Research Intern, Microsoft Research, Cambridge, UK Verifying low-level parsing in F*, with Cédric Fournet Software Engineering Intern, Google, Zürich, Switzerland Summer 2014 Honors & Awards 2022 Dennis Ritchie Doctoral Dissertation Award Honorable Mention (SIGOPS) 2022 George M. Sprowls PhD Thesis Award (MIT) 2014–2019 NSF Graduate Research Fellowship 2014 Jacobs Presidential Fellowship 2010–2014 Chancellor's Scholar Professional Service SysDW 2024 Program Committee PLDI 2024 Program Committee SySDW 2023 Program Committee

POPL 2021 Organized a tutorial "Iris — A Modular Foundation for Higher-Order Concurrent

CPP 2023 Program Committee POPL 2023 Program Committee PLDI 2022 Program Committee

Separation Logic"